Zach Wilson

Software Engineer

585-519-8701 zachjwilson1@gmail.com zachwilson.live

I am a skilled Full Stack Developer with a passion for delivering high-quality solutions that drive business success. With experience developing web applications, automating workflows, and customizing solutions to meet clients' needs, I am committed to utilizing my technical expertise and problem-solving skills to make a positive impact.

Skills

- .NET Framework, Entity Framework, C#, JQuery, JavaScript, Java, SQL, React, CSS, HTML, C, Racket, and GitHub.
- Communication, Leadership, Problem-solving, Adaptability, Time Management, and Attention to Detail.

Experience

Belvista Software / Software Developer

April 2022 - Present, Rochester, New York

- Developed a web application using .NET Framework to track time against client projects. This company-wide used app saves thousands by replacing a subscription service.
- Built custom reports in Microsoft Report Builder using SQL to generate invoices for clients.
- Build back-end C# console applications to automate several different workflow tasks for clients.
- Combination of .NET, Entity, Bootstrap, and custom CSS to create a beautiful Client Portal web application where clients access Admin and File Processing tools.
- One-on-one training with interns on codebase, code-reviews, and best-practices.

Strategic Financial Solutions / Financial Consultant

August 2019 - June 2020, Williamsville, New York

- Provided financial consultation services to 30+ clients each month.
- Managed appointments, meetings, and training with staff.
- Generated reports on Excel to help team performance.

Coast Professional Inc. / Sr. Account Manager

December 2013 - July 2019, Geneseo, New York

- Student Loan servicing to 50+ borrowers each month.
- Responsible for team performance, handling disputes, and credit card information for borrowers in absence of a manager.

Education

SUNY Oswego / Bachelor in Computer Science - 3.8 GPA

August 2021 - December 2022, Oswego, New York

SUNY JCC / Associates in Computer Science - 4.0 GPA

January 2019 - December 2020, Jamestown, New York